Kate Lawson papers, 1936-1940
George Mason University. Libraries. Special Collections & Archives
Kate Lawson papers
1936-1940
C0222
George Mason University. Libraries. Special Collections & Archives
0.25 linear feet (1 box)
The Kate Lawson papers include newspaper clippings and press releases on Federal Theatre Project productions, FTP administrative correspondence including job descriptions, memorandums on employee reclassification, complaints from employees and audience survey questionnaires, research lists, production records, and personal correspondence.
Lawson, Kate Drain
Acquisition Information
Donated to Special Collections and Archives by Kate Drain Lawson on October 31, 1977.
Related Material
The Works Progress Administration oral histories collection, the Federal Theatre Project collection, the Federal Theatre Project photograph collection, as well as numerous other personal papers.
Alternative Form Available
There are digital documents from this and other GMU FTP collections in the.
Historical Information
Born Kathryn Drain on July 27, 1894 in Spokane, Washington, her family moved to Washington, D.C., in the early 1900s. Drain left D.C. to become a nurse's aide in Paris, France, during World War I. She served in World War I in Paris as a nurse and in World War II in India with the American Red Cross. It was in Paris that she met and married John Howard Lawson, and she began her theatrical career. By 1922 she was working on Broadway as a technical director, costume and stage designer, and actress. She joined the FTP in July 1936 and headed the Bureau of Research and Publication and was the Chief Technical Officer for the FTP in New York City. She resigned in September of 1937 and moved to Los Angeles, California, to pursue a career in film and television.
Access Restrictions
There are no access restrictions.
Arrangement
Arranged alphabetically by folder title.
Scope and Content
The Kate Lawson papers include newspaper clippings and press releases on Federal Theatre Project productions, FTP administrative correspondence including job descriptions, memorandums on employee reclassification, complaints from employees and audience survey questionnaires, research lists, production records, and personal correspondence.
Index Terms
Corporate Names:
Federal Theatre Project (U.S.)
Subjects:
New Deal, 1933-1939.; Theater--United States.
Contents List
- Kate Lawson papers, 1936-1940
  - Administrative correspondence, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Letter from Kate Lawson to Hallie Flanagan
    - Letter from Hallie Flanagan to Kate Lawson
  - Federal Theatre Magazine (volume I, number V, signed by Scott McLean); TAC magazine, 1936; 1940 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Federal Theatre: presentations critical comment, May 27, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Memorandums; ephemera, 1936-1937 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous, 1934-1937 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Drawing; CCC standard stage diagram; Hallie Flanagan's farewell address to the members of the Federal Summer Theatre; Federal Theatre does biggest job of rehabilitation by Frank Merlyn.
  - Newspaper clippings and press releases, 1936-1937 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Our job with the WPA (worker's handbook), 1936 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Play Bureau (first production conference in New York City), July 22-24, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Production records (statistics and schedules), 1937 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Production attendance statistics
  - The Prompter (volume I, number I), April 18, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Research play lists and play synopses, 1936-1937 (Box 1, Folder 11)